Felipe Cardoso Moreira



felipe.cardoso.rj@gmail.com

+55 21 98587-5227



in linkedin.com/in/fellrock



Summary

Since my collage research scholarship at 2011 I've been coding alongside some project. In 2020 was my launch as a professional IT in Accenture working as a Junior Data Engineer. Just one year after I've became father and started to work as a Software Engineer at XP Inc. starting to have a bigger maturity and vision in the Tech Market. This work made me learn all about Microsoft development technologies (dotNET, C#, SQL, DevOps, Azure). After this job I've worked as a Python Developer and Tech Ops dealing with cloud and java monitoring. I'm searching for an opportunity to continue my development.

Experience



Tech Ops Engineer

Peridot Financial Solutions

Apr 2023 - Present (4 months) Main Activity: Application Support

Responsibility: Global support over Java applications deployed on cloud using AWS tools, power bi,

maintaining databases, dealing with operational task etc.

Skills: Amazon Web Services (AWS) · Communication · Java · Agile Methodologies · SQL

MJV Technology Specialist

MJV Technology & Innovation

Feb 2023 - Mar 2023 (2 months)

Main Activity: Back-End Development

Description: This project was developed for a renowned bank in Brazil using a Cloudera environment. The goal is to create a python application that extract, filter, and format data. This data will be analysed and packaged into a file for delivery to the client.

Skills: Python · Cloudera · PySpark · SQL · Agile Methodologies

Software Engineer

XP Inc.

Oct 2021 - Jan 2023 (1 year 4 months) Main activity: Web development.

Duties: Main area application update and maintenance developing pages, process and APIs.

Impact: Built 3 platform pages that helped to reduce work hours of process in more than 70%.

Skills: ASP.NET, SQL Server, Bootstrap, DevOps, JavaScript, SonarQube, Polaris, Integration and Unit

Tests, Datadog, API data collection, .NET Core, Grafana, Postman.

Data Engineer

Accenture Brasil

Nov 2020 - Oct 2021 (1 year)

Main activity: Data update.

Duties: Maintain project datasets aided by international team through manual and automatics update process that filtered and organize desire chunks of data.

Impact: The data collection made possible to elaborate complex machine learn theories that helped our client.

Skills: ETL, SQL Server, Power Bi, Pentaho Data Integration, Microsoft Power Automate, Python, PowerShell, Power Query, Excel.



Founder / CTO

Umaker

Dec 2017 - May 2020 (2 years 6 months)

As a CTO and main administrator my main duties were:

- Developing the company's strategy for using technological resources
- Analyse and know about company's problems;
- Select, hire, guide and train employees; and
- Ensuring technologies are used efficiently, profitably and securely.

Skills: Communication · Agile Methodologies · Team Leadership · Management



Digital Systems Engineer (IPqM)

Marinha do Brasil

Mar 2017 - Sep 2017 (7 months)

Main activity: Embedded software development - Internship Contract

Duties: Plan, execute and maintain navy electronic projects.

Impact: Built periscope simulator that is been used to train new specialists on Brazilian Navy.

Skills: C# · Pascal · C · OrCAD · AVR Microcontroller



Student Researcher (PIBIC)

CNPa

Sep 2011 - May 2014 (2 years 9 months)

Main Activity: Software Development - Scholarship Contract

Duties: Built a low-cost equipment to improve the experiments of the Physics lectures alongside with its own embedded software and application to make possible access data from computer.

Skills: Arduino · Pascal · Lazarus · Delphi · Circuits and Sensors.

Education

Cefet/RJ

Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Jul 2009 - Dec 2017

Core Subjects: Electrical Circuits, Electronics, Digital Systems, Digital Electronic, Economy, Technology of Semiconductors, Technical Drawing, Calculus, Complex Variables, Strength of materials, Integrated Circuits.

Munster Technological University

Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2014 - 2015

Core Subjects: Microcomputer Applications, Networks, Technological Entrepreneurship, IC Design, LabVIEW Visual Programming, Firmware Development, Digital System Design.

Licenses & Certifications

- Clean Architecture Essential ASP .NET Core com C# Udemy UC-e1690149-be38-474d-b1fd-06a6e6bb106d
- DevOps, CI/CD(Continuous Integration/Delivery for Beginners Udemy UC-2bcd6edf-e15d-4856-a963-6500f3d83bb7
- GIT and Visual Studio with Azure DevOps Repos for Developers Udemy UC-f39645a6-d5c7-47b8-af88-f67429032f65